牢记
Remember...
那天是4月12日
The date was April 12th.
航天飞机沃斯托克1号即将发射
The space shuttle is about to be launched. Vostok 1.
他曾经发射过航天飞机，但仍然没人来接他
He used to launch shuttles, but still no one comes around.
流行划过夜空
A STAR FELL FROM THE SKY
我许下一个愿望
I MADE A WISH
我希望他们都死了
I WISHED THEY ALL DIED
妈 我要问你一件事
Mom, I need to ask you something.
你那天为什么说谎？
Why did you lie that day?
当我问你那所房子是怎么被烧毁的时候 你和塞利姆为什么说谎？
You and Selim, when I asked you how that house burned down?
我为什么要撒谎？
Why would I lie?
你要做出决定
You're going to make a decision.
我会再见到你吗？
Will I see your face again?
是菲鲁兹！别开枪！我要出来了！
It's Firuz! Don't shoot! I'm coming out!
我上夜班的时候一个男人来找我
I was on night duty when a man came by.
我记得他对我说的一切
I remember everything he said to me.
他说：“你会忘记这些事，否则你会消失的 ”
"You will forget about this. Or you will disappear," he said.
-告诉我 你会放我走 -假设我放你走
- Tell me you're letting me go. - Let's say I let you go.
这些年来你所做的一切会放过你吗？
Will everything you've done all these years also let you go?
我问你是不是黑手党！
I asked you if you're mafia, son!
是，那又怎样？
Yeah. We are. So what?
好，这就是黑手党的下场
Good. Here's your mafia.
个人
PERSONAL
兄弟
Bro...
德瓦，这真是一个不可思议的想法
This is an incredible idea, Deva.
-看到了吧 -是的
- You see it, right? - Yeah. I see it.
有多少人在这里留言？
How many people have written in?
好像他们已经等了一辈子了
It's as if they've waited their whole lives for this moment.
等待别人问他们的意见
Waiting for someone to ask them their opinion.
这里有一些很好的回复
There are some great replies here.
听着
Here are some. Listen up.
你想让狗杀手杀死谁？
Whom would you like Dog Slayer to kill?
他应该杀死坐在公园长椅上的人
He should kill the people who sit around on park benches,
吃着坚果 乱扔垃圾
eating nuts and scattering trash everywhere.
还有这个
Here's another one.
如果他杀死不停按喇叭的人，那不是很好吗？
Wouldn't it be great if he killed the ones who refuse to stop honking?
还真是不错
It would be.
还有这个
Here's another one.
你是否觉得当你排队的时候
You know how when you're waiting in line
你背后的人离你太近了吗？
and the person behind you is standing too close to you?
他应该杀死他们，以便我们放松下来
He should kill them so we can finally breathe.
让我看看
Let me see.
“亲爱的狗杀手”
"Dear Dog Slayer..."
“我妈妈禁止我上网”
My mom forbade me from going on the internet
“因为我在学校学习不好，能请你杀死我妈妈吗？”
"because I'm doing bad at school. Could you please kill my mom?"
-上面这样写的 -他要他杀死他的妈妈？
- So it says. - He wants him to kill his mom?
看来是的，你看他的昵称
It seems so. Look at his nickname.
复仇的一代
Vengeful generation.
所以这位穆罕默德·尤特吉尔去找过医生
So this Mehmet Yurtgil went to the doctor.
他威胁医生并通过恐吓使他闭嘴
He threatened the doctor and shut him up by scaring him.
然后，医生被强迫撰写有关乌福克的报告
And then, he forces him to write this report about Ufuk.
-是吗 -是的长官
- Is that so? - Yes, sir.
并且第一位受害者就是穆罕默德·尤尔吉尔
And the first victim is this Mehmet Yurtgil.
你还记得我告诉过我我是从50位女性中选出你的吗？
You remember when I told you that I'd picked you from among 50 women?
谢谢你没有让我失望 我还有另一件事要感谢你
Thank you for not letting me down. I have another thing to thank you on.
前几天，当我们在我的房间里聊天时
The other day, when we were talking in my room
我告诉你发生的事情可能与坎布拉无关
and I told you that what's happening might have nothing to do with Kambura...
你知道你是怎么问我这个文件的吗？你怎么不放弃呢？
You know how you asked me for the file? How you didn't give up on it?
也谢谢你
Thank you for that, as well.
干得好 我们越来越接近了
Good job. We're getting closer.
好先生这次写了什么？
What did the good sir write this time?
他们都是相同的字眼
They all had the same word written on them.
“个人”
"Personal."
“个人” 所以他是出于个人原因杀死了他们，是吗？
"Personal." So he killed them for his own reasons, huh?
-似乎如此 -那么……
- Seems so. - Then...
他为谁杀了这些人？他们是什么人？
Whom did he kill all these people for? Who are they?
长官，这些人有80个前科
Chief, these men had 80 priors.
同谋罪 伪造罪 这些人的前科值得一看
Accessory. Forgery. Their rap sheet is something to behold.
但他们都与坎布拉无关 也没有找到任何指纹
But they're not connected to Kambura. No fingerprints, either.
但犯罪过程被监控拍了下来
But the crime was caught on CCTV.
我猜一定是穿了猫服装
Let me guess. Cat costume.
是的
Yes.
我们能够通过附近商店的摄像机跟着他走了很长时间
We were able to follow him a long while through neighborhood shops' cameras.
他进出几条街
He went in and out of a few streets.
他的举动就像他不确定他应该去往哪个方向
He acted like he wasn't sure which way he was supposed to be headed.
他进入一个建筑工地，因为整个区域都是一个建筑工地
He went into a construction site, because that whole area is a construction site
而且里面没有摄像头，所以我们跟丢了
and there are no cameras looking inside, we lost the suspect.
由于城市改造项目 所以跟丢了
We lost him because of the urban transformation project.
他有逃跑计划
He had his escape planned.
这些建筑工地就像我们城市中心的黑洞
Those construction sites are like black holes in the middle of our cities.
这很糟糕 这真的很糟糕
This is bad. This is really bad.
这真的很糟糕 每个人都在搭顺风车
This is really bad. Everyone's getting on the ride.
谁有骨气，谁就开枪，谁就杀人，谁就嫁祸于他!
Whoever has a bone to pick will shoot, kill, and blame him!
那么我们怎么与坎布拉联系起来
So we have the Kambura connection.
你怎么看？
What do you think?
塔亚尔·凯马克，那天晚上被烧死在房子里的人
Tayyar Kaymak, who died in the house that night,
他有一个兄弟叫做哈姆萨·凯马克
has a brother, Hamza Kaymak.
我们认为他可能知道一些事
We think he might know something.
也许他是杀手 也许他想为他兄弟报仇
Maybe he's the killer. Maybe he wants to avenge his brother.
不，长官
No, sir.
在凶手杀人期间他因抢劫而入狱
He was in prison for mugging someone while the murders were being committed.
他在监狱里吗？好吧
He's in prison, huh? Fine. Alright.
但是他一定知道什么事情 毕竟他是塔亚尔的兄弟，不是吗？
But he has to know something. He's Tayyar's brother after all, right?
我们需要搞清楚他知道些什么 去监狱和他谈谈
We need to find out what he knows. Go to his prison and talk to him.
他越狱了
He escaped.
当我们试图将乌福克从坎布拉开出来的时候
He fled the night when we were trying to get Ufuk out of Kambura.
现在有人在追捕他
There's a manhunt for him right now.
不可能……
No way...
看，塞法？又一次越狱
See, Sefa? Another escape.
别这样长官 那是一次错误的判断
Come on, Chief. It was a lapse of judgement.
他是自首的，我怎么可能预料到他会逃跑？
He handed himself in. How could I've known he'd try that?
好吧 总之 我们接下来这样做
Anyway. Fine. Here's what we're going to do.
内芙拉，你去追捕塔亚尔的兄弟
Nevra, you go after Tayyar's brother.
把他的照片打印出来 分发出去
Get print-outs of his mugshot. Spread them around.
如果他在外面，有人会看到他的
If he's out there, someone will have seen him.
塞法，你去收集有关被烧毁房屋的更多信息
Sefa, you gather more information on the house that burned down.
任何记得或知道那晚事情的人
Anyone who remembers or knows something about that night...
把坎布拉的所有人都询问一遍
Get the whole Kambura in here for interrogation.
-行动 -是的 长官
- Let's go. - Right away, Chief.
这样不行的
This is not going to work out.
如果我在杀掉所有人之前就病的不行了怎么办？
What if I get really sick before I do all these people in?
然后
Then...
首先
First...
你好
Hello.
你有遗愿吗？
Do you have a last wish?
没有？
No?
你有？
You do?
原谅我，但我不在乎
Forgive me, but I don't give a toss.
你好？
Hello?
是？
Yes?
谁？
Who?
你说谁？
Who, did you say?
-哈姆萨·凯马克，对吗？-是的，阿提斯，这真的很紧急
- Hamza Kaymak, right? - Yes, Ates, it's really urgent.
别担心，半小时之内到处都是他的照片
Don't worry. His photos will be everywhere in half an hour.
谢谢
Thank you.
我什么时候能见到你？
When will I see you?
我不知道我什么时候可以离开这里
I don't know when I'll be able to get out of here.
你有回过家吗？
Do you go home at all?
-有时候回去，是的 -我能去吗？
- Sometimes, yes. - Can I come?
来吧
Come.
好的
Alright.
-菲鲁兹 -什么事？
- Firuz... - Yeah?
你有什么？
What do you have?
菲鲁兹，这不会给我带来麻烦吧？
Firuz, this won't get me in trouble, right?
得了吧 菲科！你认识我多少年了
Come on, Fiko! You've known me for years.
放松 你会没事的
Relax. You'll be fine.
这是什么？你找到了什么？
What is this? What did you find?
我在犯罪现场发现了一些不属于受害者的鲜血
I found some blood on the crime scene that doesn't belong to the victims.
可能属于嫌疑犯
Probably belongs to the suspect.
-这是DNA报告吗？ -是的
- Is this the DNA report on it? - Yes.
好
Good.
给你
Here.
不要把所有的钱都花在一个地方
Don't spend it all in one place.
这不在你提供给其他人的文件中，对吗？
This isn't in the file you provided the others, right?
-你把这些挑出来了？ -是的
- You threw it out, right? - Yes. I did.
-回见 -菲鲁兹你儿子怎么样？
- I'll see you around. - Firuz. How's your boy doing?
老样子
The same. No change.
这是什么？
What's this?
德瓦，过来看看这个
Deva, take a look at this. Come here.
那不是在丛林中发现的尸体吗？
Isn't that the corpse that was found in the jungle?
萨利姆还是谁？
Salim or something?
但是他们在那里做什么？
But what are they doing there?
他们是什么人？
Who are they?
我不知道 回复他们 认识一下
I don't know. Respond to them and let's get acquainted.
等等，小姐
One second. One second, miss.
冷静一下
Calm down for one second.
你看到了照片中那个人，对不对？
You saw the man from the photos, right?
好的
Alright.
你在哪里看到他的？
Where did you see him?
在梦中？
In a dream?
你在梦中看到他
You saw him in a dream.
祝你好梦，小姐
Sweet dreams, miss.
-真不可思议 -耐心一点 可能会有好事发生
- This is impossible. - Be patient. Something might turn up.
你在做什么？
What are you doing?
我正在列出坎布拉人的名单
I'm making a list of the Kamburan gentry.
明天去坎布拉
Tomorrow is the Kambura Day at the station.
我可能会告诉他们我是他们的新领导人
I might tell them I'm their new leader.
喂？接进来
Hello? Connect them.
内芙拉，我也会叫你妈妈的丈夫
Nevra, I'm calling your mom's husband in, as well.
先生，我在听
I'm listening, sir.
你在哪里看到他的？
Where did you see him?
什么时候？
When?
请不要浪费我的时间
Please stop wasting my time.
艾汉
Ayhan?
-艾汉，祝你一切顺利 -谢谢，阿加
- Ayhan, good luck with all this. - Thanks, Agah.
我们正在尽力整理
We're doing our best to tidy up.
昨晚我很抱歉
I'm sorry about last night.
你难得参加我们的活动，但愿并没有那么令人不愉快
You join us once in a blue moon, I wish it hadn't been so unpleasant.
没有不愉快 这是一场真正的灾难
It wasn't unpleasant. It was a proper disaster.
那是什么？我很高兴我们起身离开了
What was that? I'm so glad we up and left.
我也不想被打 我还有一个女伴和我一起
I wouldn't want to get beat up. I had a lady friend with me, too.
我们好害怕
We were so scared.
你和这些男人有什么关系？
What business do you have with such men?
别担心，阿加没有什么可害怕的
Don't worry, Agah. There's nothing left to be scared of.
你是什??么意思，如果他们回来了怎么办？
What do you mean? What if they come back?
他们当晚被枪杀了 三个人都死了
They were shot that night. All three are dead.
不是吧！
No way!
毕竟，不是每个人都像我们一样
Really. Not everyone's like us, after all.
他们一定是找了错误的目标
They must've gone after the wrong types.
试图勒索他，反被枪杀
Tried to extort him, and got shot.
伊斯坦布尔变得面目全非
Istanbul has become unrecognizable.
杀人不应该那么容易
It shouldn't be this easy to kill people.
看看你有多轻松的谈论这件事
Look how relaxed you are, talking about it.
我已经不认识伊斯坦布尔了，尤其是贝尤鲁
I don't recognize Istanbul anymore. Especially not Beyoglu.
哦，那个老贝尤鲁 那个亲爱的老贝尤鲁
Oh, that old Beyoglu... That dear old Beyoglu...
我能说什么？如果你是对的，你就是对的
What can I say? When you're right, you're right.
可悲的是，我们收到很多报告
Sadly, we've been getting reports
疗养院对住户的虐待最近越来越多
of mistreatment of residents from nursing homes more and more lately.
但是，我们现在是一家一流的养老院
However, we're at a stellar nursing home right now.
这有一位住户 让我们问她一些问题
We have a resident with us. Let's ask her some questions.
你在这里开心吗？你想说什么吗？
Are you happy here? Would you like to say anything?
我65岁了
I turned 65.
你看起来很棒 我希望你能长命百岁
You look great. I hope you see many more years yet.
在上一个生日，我又许了一个愿望
On my last birthday, I made another wish.
-像个孩子一样 -太好了
- Like a child. - That's great.
当然，这是另一个不可能的愿望
It was another impossible wish, of course.
也许是不可能的，但我希望成真
It might not be. I hope it comes true.
你知道我想要什么吗？
You know what I wished for?
成为一个好人
To become a good person.
-太好了，我们都应该朝这个方向努力 -她记得一切
- Great. We should all aspire to that. - She remembers everything.
阿加 你到底对她有什么兴趣
What is it, Agah? You're awfully interested in her.
不，我对电视更感兴趣
No. I'm more interested in the TV.
我老了 我可能会买一台
Mine's getting old. I might get one of these.
你喜欢这里吗？你来这里多久了？
Do you like it here? How long have you been here?
水晶般清澈
It's crystal clear.
每当我来这里
Whenever I come here,
电视上都有节目
something's on the TV.
-反正祝你好运 -谢谢 照顾好自己
- Anyway... Good luck to you. - Thanks. Take care of yourself.
整理一下，我们要重新开张了
Come on. Tidy it up. We're about to open back up.
来吧，我们需要整理一下 客人就快来了
Come on. We need to tidy the place up. Customers are on the way.
对于老年痴呆症患者，如果处于晚期
So with Alzheimer's, let's say it's at an advanced stage.
一切都结束了 病人什么都不记得
It's all over. The patient remembers nothing.
完全脱离世界
Completely disconnected from the world.
-嗯？-他们会突然想起来吗？
- Yes? - Might they suddenly remember?
他们会恢复记忆吗？
Might they get their memory back?
那有可能吗？有可能发生吗？
Is that possible? Is that a possibility? Does that happen?
你为什么要问我这个？你还没到那个阶段
Why are you asking me this? You're not at that stage yet.
现在担心这样的事情还为时过早
It's too early to be worrying about stuff like this.
我正在考虑所有的可能
I'm pondering every eventuality.
值得期待，那有可能吗？
It's worth hoping for. Is it possible at all?
我意识到有一天我会忘记一切
I realize that I'll forget everything some day.
但是我问你这是否有可能
But I'm asking you if this is a possibility.
阿加！
Agah!
老年痴呆症
Alzheimer's...
仍然笼罩在神秘之中
Is still shrouded in mystery.
每个人都是例外
Each person is an exception.
每个病人的发展情况都不一样
Each case progresses differently.
但总的来说，几乎不可能
But in general, that's outside the realm of possibility.
可能性，例外情况呢？ 你什么也没说！
Possibilities, exceptions. You're not saying anything!
我问你是否可能！
I'm asking you if it's possible or not!
还记得我告诉过你关于突然爆发的愤怒吗？
Remember when I told you about sudden bursts of anger?
我不想谈论我的愤怒！回答我！
I don't want to talk about my bursts! Answer me!
你现在正遇到这些突发事件中的一种情况
You're having one of those bursts right now.
因为你不回答！
Because you don't answer!
因为你的问题没有答案！
Because your question doesn't have an answer!
原谅我
Forgive me.
我的意思是
I mean...
即使没有已知病例
Even if there are no known cases...
但这是有可能的
It's possible.
你现在放松一下怎么样？
How about you relax now?
深呼吸 放松一下……
Take a few deep breaths through the nose. Relax...
我以后可以放松！我现在不能放松！我还有工作要做！
I can relax later! I can't relax now! I have work to do!
-我要离开，如果你允许的话 -阿加
- I'm leaving, with your permission. - Agah...
是？
Yes?
-你在忙什么？-我不是……什么意思？
- Are you up to something? - I don't... What do you mean?
你已经停止服药了吗？
Have you stopped taking your medication?
当然不是 我正在服用药物
Of course not. I'm taking my meds.
-确定吗-是的
- Are you sure? - Yes.
好吧，下次预约时，请带上祖哈尔
Alright. For your next appointment, please bring Zuhal along.
不好意思？为什么？
Excuse me? Why?
祖哈尔是患者还是我是患者？她为什么需要在这里？
Is Zuhal the patient or am I? Why does she need to be here?
好 好
Alright, fine.
好 我带女儿来
Fine. I'll bring my daughter along.
我怎么进去？
How will I get in?
从哪里进去？
Where will I get in?
可怜的阿加
You poor Agah.
你怎样……
How will you...
当然不能
Of course you can't.
你真是活该，没做准备就来了
Serves you right for coming so unprepared.
你不会长出翅膀来跳过围墙 对吧？
You're not about to sprout wings and jump over the fence, are you?
再次问好
Hello again.
你告诉我如果有需要时就找你
You told me to come see you if I needed anything.
不管需要什么
No matter what, you said.
我需要个东西
I need something.
你愿意为我去死吗？
Could you please die for me?
这些是什么？
What are these?
最好的野餐
The best picnics...
都是在家里吃的
Are those had at home, Nevra.
我拿进来
I'll take that. Come in.
-有关于塔亚尔兄弟的消息吗？-没有
- Any news on Tayyar's brother? - No.
其实有几个女人打电话来
There are, actually. Some woman called.
告诉我她在梦中看到他
Told me she saw him in her dreams.
-听起来怎么样？-听起来很棒
- How does that sound? - Sounds great.
总比没有好
It's better than nothing.
你什么时候搬来的？
When did you move in here?
如你所见，我还没真正搬进来
As you can see, I never really did.
像这样六个月了
It's been like this for like six months.
我觉得很好看
I think it looks nice.
也许我应该用你的房间来装饰我的房间
Maybe I should decorate my place after yours.
我认为这是个好主意，一切都整理好了，你知道吗？
I think that's a great idea. Everything's all tidied up, you see?
另外，当你要搬走的时候都不需要打包
Plus, when you want to move out, you don't have to do any packing up.
为什么？你打算去某个地方吗？
Why? Are you planning to go somewhere?
我总是去某个地方，阿提斯
I always go somewhere, Ates.
你看不出来，但我经常离开我的身体
You can't tell from the outside, but I very often leave my body.
-轮到你了-轮到什么了？
- It's your turn. - What turn?
我已经告诉过你关于我的一切
I've told you everything about me.
告诉你我已经腐烂多年了
Told you I've been rotting for years.
我想要的就是再次成为那个以前的阿提斯
That all I want is to become that old Ates again.
那个刚从大学毕业的阿提斯
That Ates who just got out of college.
仍然相信新闻的阿提斯
That Ates who still believes in journalism.
我已经给你看了我所有的伤疤 让你看到了我所有的痛苦
I've shown you all my scars. Let you see all my pain.
该你告诉我了
It's your turn to tell me.
首先，告诉我那天晚上你为什么来我家
First, tell me why you knocked on my door that night.
你知道当你说……
You know how you say...
你想要的就是再次成为那个以前的阿提斯
That all you want is to become that old Ates again...
我正好相反
I'm the exact opposite.
我最担心的是成为以前的内芙拉
What I fear most is becoming the old Nevra.
为什么？
Why?
我认为……
I think...
我不知道如何与人共存
I don't know how to co-exist with people.
如何与人交谈
How to talk to people.
与朋友做什么
What to do with friends.
如何与男友共度时光
How to spend time with a boyfriend.
如何管理你与他人之间的空间
How to manage the space between you and someone else.
我不知道该怎么做
I don't know how to do any of that.
但是我一直假装知道
But I've always pretended to know.
而且我总是错的
And I was always wrong.
我有谈过恋爱 但我真的根本不想谈
I've had relationships I really didn't want at all.
我有一些我从未喜欢过的朋友
I've had friends that I never liked.
我不能拒绝任何人
I couldn't say no to anyone.
我不知道为什么
I don't know why,
但我总是非常关心人们对我的看法
but I always cared so much about what people thought about me.
以为我不得不让每个人都开心
As thought I had to make everyone happy.
因为
Because...
你是
You're...
好人
Good.
不是
No.
因为我软弱
Because I'm weak.
我实在很软弱
I'm so weak, in fact,
我不敢打开那些盒子，然后又变成以前的内芙拉
that I'm scared of opening those boxes and running into the old Nevra in them.
那天晚上我敲了你的门，
I knocked on your door that night,
因为那天晚上我真的很寂寞
because I felt really lonely that night.
那个我不想再成为的老内芙拉
The old Nevra, the one I never want to become again,
过去常常把自己扔进别人的怀里
used to fling herself into some guy's arms
每当她感到孤独时
whenever she felt lonely.
塞……
Ce... Ce...
塞米尔！
Cemil!
那天晚上我和谁在一起？
Whom was I with on that night?
是你 还是
You, or...
曾经的内芙拉？
The old Nevra?
曾经的内芙拉……
The old Nevra...
曾经的内芙拉
The old Nevra
现在可能会和其他人在一起
would probably be with someone else right now.
那是我逃离的地方，阿提斯
That's what I ran away from, Ates.
塞米尔，他有枪，塞米尔
Cemil, he has a gun, Cemil.
塞米尔
Cemil...
塞米尔！
Cemil!
-你待在里面 -好吧，你小心
- You stay inside. - OK, be careful.
我逃离了自己
I ran away from myself.
这就是为什么我想要新的生活
That's why I wanted a new life.
没有人认识我的生活
A life where no one knew me.
更准确地说……
To be more accurate...
是没有那些自以为了解我的人的生活
A life without people who think they know me.
这就是为什么我辞职并重新开始
That's why I resigned and started over.
塞米尔！
Cemil!
塞米尔
Cemil...
这里没有人
There's no one here.
刚刚还有
There was.
是他
It was him.
-谁？-连环杀手
- Who? - The serial killer.
他穿着猫服装到处杀人
He's on everywhere. He wears a cat costume.
他刚刚就在那里 手里拿着枪
He was there. He had a gun in his hand.
-但是没有人 -他一定已经逃跑了
- But there's no one around. - He must've run away.
也许你吓到他了
Maybe you scared him.
真可笑
Funny.
祖哈尔，你有没有意识到你救了我的命？
Do you realize, Zuhal, that you saved my life?
如果是我开的门 我想我绝对不会吓跑他
If I'd answered the door, I doubt he'd have been scared of me.
-我们进去吧 -好
- Let's go inside. - Sure. Let's.
塞米尔！
Cemil!
这是我第一次和别人说这些话
This is the first time I'm telling someone all this.
奇怪吧
Strange, right?
你追逐自己，我逃避自己
You chasing yourself, and me running away from myself.
我认为这就是……
That's exactly why, I think...
我们将成为完美情侣的原因
We'll be a perfect couple.
-你知道我们的首要任务是什么吗？-什么？
- You know our first order of business? - What?
你什么都没吃 为什么不吃？
You didn't eat anything. Why aren't you eating?
你跟你妈妈聊过吗？
Have you spoken to your mom?
昨晚她发短信住在朋友还是什么人的家
She texted last night. Staying over at a friend's or something.
-她今天应该回来 -这个朋友是谁？
- She should be back today. - Who is this friend?
-我不知道-你不好奇吗？
- I don't know. - Aren't you curious?
她是一个成年人，我为什么要好奇？
She's an adult. Why would I be?
你什么意思，为什么？这是酒店吗？
What do you mean, why? Is this a hotel?
随时签入或签出
Check in or out whenever you'd like.
你一直是这样啊
You do it all the time.
我们不介意你呆在女友的家里
We don't mind you staying at your girlfriend's.
闭嘴
Stop running your mouth.
你真可笑
You're being ridiculous.
-你在生什么气吗？-为什么我会生气！
- Are you mad about something? - Why would I be mad!
她应该让我们知道 “我在这里，我会回来的”
She should've let us know. "I'll be here. I'll be back by this time."
你是在跟我说话，还是在盯着那个屏幕？
Are you talking to me, or are you staring at that screen?
同时
I can do both.
不行，你不能边听我说话还边玩手机
No you can't listen and do that at the same time. Drop it.
好吧，我不玩了
Fine. I've dropped it.
-那是什么？-什么？
- What's that? - What's what?
-那让我看看 -给……
- That. Let me see that. - Here...
-这是什么？-你都忘了吗？
- What's this? - You're completely oblivious then, huh?
你没看新闻吗？
You don't watch the news?
他是连环杀手 第一个真正的土耳其连环杀手
He's a serial killer. The first real Turkish serial killer.
你怎么知道是他？也可能是女人
How do you know it's a he? It might be a woman.
当然有可能
That's possible, of course.
你为什么要贴在那里？
Why did you stick that on there?
因为他在做不可思议的事情
Because he's doing incredible stuff.
杀人有什么不可思议的？
What's incredible about killing people?
那取决于你要杀谁
Depends on who you're killing.
早上好
Good morning.
他们收到一个情报，这次看起来很可靠
They received another tip. It seems legit this time.
除了野餐的剩菜，家里没有任何吃的东西
There's nothing to eat around the house except for our picnic's leftovers.
我会没事的，去拯救世界吧，以便我以后写文章
I'll be fine. Go save the world so I can write about it later.
我走了
I'm going.
一路来到我的前门
Came all the way to my front door.
到这里
To the house.
到我家
To my house.
我知道这会发生
I knew this was going to happen.
我就知道
I knew it.
如果要杀坎布兰人，凶手迟早要来到我家门口
If you're killing Kamburans, you're going to end up at my door sooner or later.
我现在该怎么办？
What am I supposed to do now? Tell me.
我该埋葬谁，埋在哪里？给我些东西
Whom do I bury and where? Give me something.
我们有DNA报告 我在实验室里有关系
We have the DNA report. I have a connection in the lab.
他把文件给了我，其他人都不知道
He gave me the file without the others knowing.
从8000万人的DNA中找到他
Run it against the DNA of 80 million people.
这个人和坎布拉有什么过节？
What's this guy's beef with Kambura?
你的人在那里做什么？
What's your people doing there?
在坎布拉有一座被烧毁的房子
There's this burnt-down house in Kambura.
他们正在寻找在大火中丧生的人的兄弟
They're looking for the brother of the man who died in the fire.
是哈姆萨
Yeah. Hamza.
-哈姆萨·凯马克先生 -是的 就是他
- Mister Hamza Kaymak. - Yes, that's his name.
-他是越狱的逃犯 -我知道，是我安排的
- He's a fugitive. Escaped from prison. - I know. Because I arranged it.
哈姆萨不知道那些事情，他甚至都不认识我
Hamza doesn't know about that part, of course. He wouldn't even know me.
怎么了菲鲁兹？为什么感到惊讶？
What is it, Firuz? Why are you surprised?
你以为我没有在其他地方工作的朋友吗？
You thought I didn't have other friends working in other places?
你是这样想的吗？
Is that what you thought?
你知道哈姆萨现在在哪里吗？
Do you know where Hamza is now?
如今，感恩已是一个逐渐消失的概念，我也不知道他在哪里
Gratitude is a dying concept these days. I don't know where he is, sadly.
那个叫哈姆萨的罪犯逃离了让他越狱的人
That ingrate called Hamza ran away from the people who broke him out.
那你为什么把他从监狱里救出来？
Why did you get him out of prison, then?
因为我知道你搞不定乌福克
Because I knew you'd fail with Ufuk,
所以我决定自己动手
I decided to take matters into my own hands.
好吧，但是乌福克与哈姆萨有什么关系？
Fine, but what does Ufuk have to do with Hamza?
菲鲁兹，你所了解的越少
Firuz, the less you know,
睡得越香
the easier you'll sleep.
这样，你就不会来找我放过你
That way, you won't come to me asking me to let you go.
知道了？
Got that?
今天有很多来自坎布拉的人
We have lots of people coming in from Kambura today.
调查被烧毁的房子
Looking into the burnt-down house.
你知道我们在说什么吗，祖哈尔？
You know what we were just talking about, Zuhal?
为什么看到你时他会放下枪？
Why do you think he lowered his gun when he saw you?
他不想杀了你 他是冲我来的
He didn't want to kill you. He was here for me.
他为什么不进屋？
Why didn't he come inside?
我的意思是……
I mean...
我不知道
I don't know.
-你不觉得奇怪吗？-很奇怪
- Don't you find it strange? - Very strange.
也许他改变了主意 我不知道
Maybe he changed his mind. I don't know.
是否有可能他后悔了？
Isn't it possible that he regretted it?
杀人并不容易
It's not that easy, taking a life.
好吧，祖哈尔，这取决于你要杀死谁
Well, Zuhal, that depends on whom you're killing.
嗯 桑古尔
Yes, Sungur.
那房子为什么被烧毁了？谁把它烧了？
Why did that house burn down? Who burned it down?
我不知道是谁烧了它，
I don't know who burned it down,
但我们都以为塔亚尔是个小偷
but we all thought Tayyar was a thief.
我的意思是……
I mean...
消息四处流传
Word was going around.
小偷把我逼疯了
Thieves drive me up the walls.
如果他来找我们，告诉我们他需要帮助，我们会尽力帮助他
If he came to us, telling us needed help, we would've given him everything.
但是你非要偷东西？
But stealing? Come on.
我们看到一群人围在房子周围
We saw a crowd gathering around the house.
所以我和孩子们一起过去了
So I went over with the kids.
突然就起火了
Suddenly, a fire started.
我们想把火扑灭
We wanted to put it out...
-但是不行 -你做不到
- But couldn't. - You couldn't.
-打扰一下-嗨
- Excuse me. - Hi.
我在找卡穆兰·盖兹奇 有人告诉我他在这里工作
I'm looking for Kamuran G?zcü. They told me he worked here.
卡穆兰？在那边
Brother Kamuran? Over there.
-谢谢-不客气
- Thank you. - Don't mention it.
你好 我是来自凶杀科的内芙拉·艾尔玛斯
Good day. Murder Bureau. Nevra Y?lmaz.
我在找卡穆兰·盖兹奇
I'm looking for Kamuran G?zcü.
来吧，我就是卡穆兰
Come on in. I'm Kamuran.
坐
Take a seat.
你说你知道哈姆萨·凯马克
You said you knew Hamza Kaymak.
我当然认识他
I know him, of course.
他昨天就坐在那里帮助我们清理了贻贝
He sat right there just yesterday. Helped us clean the mussels.
然后他听到一些话就开始惊慌
Then he got word of something and started panicking.
他昨晚跟某人交谈，今早就不见了
He apparently talked to someone last night. He was gone in the morning.
-他可能去了哪里？-我不知道
- Where might he have gone? - I wouldn't know.
保加利亚，希腊……与他交谈的人是人贩子
Bulgaria, Greece... The guy he talked to smuggles people.
我们的一个孩子偷听到了
One of the boys overheard them.
哈姆萨……
And Hamza...
可能是为了付钱给人犯，他拿走了我们留在这里的所有钱
Probably to pay that smuggler, he took all the money we kept here.
我恳求你
Look... I implore you.
如果找到那个人，请把我们的钱要回来
If you find that man, ask him about our money.
那是他们的血汗钱
It was for their honest work.
我什么都不记得了，孩子 我一点都不知道
I don't remember anything, son. I wouldn't know anything at all.
塞利姆…… 塞利姆叔叔
Selim... Uncle Selim.
你一定听说过
You must've overheard something.
我知道你那天晚上不在
You weren't there that night. I know.
但是人们没有谈论这件事吗？一定有人说起过
But didn't people talk about it around Kambura? They must have.
好
Well...
我们那里的人不喜欢外国人
Our people don't like foreigners.
当然不是我
Not me, of course. But...
我一点也不歧视
I don't discriminate at all.
但是我的意思是
But... I mean...
-原因可能是 -因为他是外国人
- That might be why. - Because he was a foreigner.
当然
Sure.
外国人与我们不同
Foreigners are different to us.
是与我们不同
Different to us. Yes.
阿提斯
Ates...
你写过一篇关于人贩的文章
You ran a story on human smugglers.
里面有采访之类的东西 我需要找到他们中的一人
It had interviews and stuff in it. I need to get a hold of one of them.
我不在乎是谁
I don't care who.
好吧，我在那里见
Alright. I'll see you there.
没人用铁链锁门
Nobody put chains on anything.
谁告诉你有人用铁链锁住了门窗？
Who told you they put chains on the windows and doors?
我们到的时候全是大火
It was all ablaze when we arrived.
乌福克哭了，想进去救人
Ufuk was crying out, trying to get inside.
我们已经尽力了，但那是不可能的
We did our best, but it was impossible.
我们在阻止乌福克和试图扑灭大火之间左右为难。
We were torn between holding Ufuk back and trying to put out the fire.
就在那时 一根横梁掉下来砸中乌福克的头
That's when something fell on Ufuk's head. A beam or something.
他本来就是个笨蛋
He was already a half-wit.
在那之后，他变得很奇怪
After that, he became really strange.
你当时在哪里干什么？
What were you doing there?
乌福克一直在说那些话
Ufuk had been talking about it a while.
说是他烧掉了房子 是他杀掉了塔亚尔一家
Saying he'd burn that place down, saying he'd kill Tayyar.
当我们看到乌福克奔向房屋时，我们紧跟着他
When we saw Ufuk running to the house, we followed him.
阻止他做一些愚蠢的事情，但是我们不能
To stop him from doing something stupid. But we couldn't.
乌福克为什么要杀死塔亚尔一家？
Why did Ufuk want to kill Tayyar?
是因为他是小偷，还是因为他是吉普赛人？为什么？
Because he was a thief, or because he was Romani? Why?
他疯了，我告诉你 你不能问一个疯子做事的原因
He's mad, I'm telling you. You can't ask a madman why he did what.
就我所知，塔亚可能没给他好脸色
Tayyar might've given him dirty looks, for all I know.
这是个小地方
It's a small place.
除了争吵外别无他法
There's nothing to do but bicker.
你以为和我女儿在一起就能不死了吗？
You think being involved with my daughter makes you immortal?
好的
Alright.
如果你暂时不死
If you're not going to bleed for now,
谁来代替你？
whom would you like to take your place?
你该死的兄弟怎么样？
How about your blood brother?
那行得通，对吗？那行得通
That works, right? That works beautifully.
我认为那太诗意了
I think that would be so poetic.
你好
Hello.
你在找谁
Who are you looking for.
-我们在找吕泰-我不认识他
- We're looking for Anchor Rü?tü. - I don't know him.
有人告诉我们在库姆卡皮的每个人都认识他
They told us everyone in Kumkap? would know him.
尤其是你
Especially you.
肯定是误会
There must've been a mistake.
我什么都不知道 我不认识这个人
I don't know anything. I don't know any Rü?tü.
我们不是冲你来的，只需告诉我吕泰在哪里
We aren't after you. Just tell me where Anchor Rü?tü is.
-这条街-在哪里？
- There's this street. - Where is it?
成交
You have a deal.
吕泰？
Anchor Rü?tü?
是的 你想要什么
Yes? What do you want?
我需要一个名叫哈姆萨·凯马克的人
I want this man. His name is Hamza Kaymak.
这跟我有什么关系
What does it have to do with me?
他付钱给走私犯带他过境
He paid a smuggler to take him across the border.
我怎么会知道走私犯？
Why would I know about smugglers?
-你不走私吗？-你在说什么？当然不是
- Aren't you a smuggler? - What are you talking about? No.
我天生真的很镇定
I'm actually really calm by nature.
我不喜欢生气
I don't like getting mad.
但是我真的很着急，你想看到我着急的样子吗？
But I'm in a real hurry. Would you like to see me get mad in a hurry?
如果我想呢？
What if you did?
我该怎么做……
What would I do...
我可能首先要让你个子弹
I might start with making you eat the shells, for a start.
车牌记下来了吗
Do you have the license plate down? Alright.
通过广播宣布
Announce it over the radio.
白色小型货车将在两个小时内离开托普哈内
The white minivan will be leaving Tophane in two hours.
它携带着非法移民和在逃的哈姆萨·凯马克
It's carrying illegal aliens and the fugitive Hamza Kaymak.
我现在把细节发给你 我正在路上
I'm sending you all the info. I'm on my way.
内芙拉
Nevra...
你是不是刚刚因为一个人把坚果壳扔在地上就用枪指着他？
Did you just point a gun at a man for throwing nuts on the ground?
我可以做得更好
I can do you one better.
前几天我梦见公牛
I saw a bull in my dream the other day.
我用枪指着那头可怜的牛
I pointed my gun at that poor creature.
嗯……
Um...
我要去报社了
I should head to the paper.
去收拾一下我的办公室
I'll clean up my office a bit.
谢谢
Thank you.
我希望你能找到想要的东西
I hope you find what you're looking for.
已经找到了
I already have.
-接下来发生了什么？-接下来什么都没发生
- What happened next? - Next, nothing...
他用枪指着我
He pointed his gun at me.
他看着我，放下了枪
He took a good look at me, and lowered his gun.
当然 我关上了门
I shut the door, of course.
当我们去寻找他时，他走了
When we went looking for him, he was gone.
-你没给警察打电话吗？-当然报警了！
- You didn't call the cops? - Of course we did. Of course!
你一定很害怕
You must've been so scared.
当时真的很恐怖
It was really scary in the moment.
但是现在回想一下
But thinking about it now...
在那一刻，他看着我的时候……
There was this moment when he took a good look at me...
持续了几秒钟 我感觉到了一些东西……
It went on for a few seconds. I felt something...
-我觉得有些奇怪-你感觉到了什么？
- I felt something really strange. - What did you feel?
我的意思是……有点像……
I mean... It was almost like...
像是我确定他永远都不会伤害我
Like I was sure he'd never hurt me.
好奇怪
It was so strange.
是的，确实是
Yes. It really is.
我是说，我的一生
I mean, my whole life,
我从未如此确定某人不会伤害我
I've never been so sure that someone wasn't going to hurt me.
你明白我的意思吗？
Do you get what I'm saying? Never!
不管是谁，除了你，当然
No matter whom! Except for you, of course.
但是，你看，这件事已经深深印在了我的脑海中
But look... Look, this is burned onto my mind.
我当时真的很小 八岁也许九岁
I'm really little. Eight years old. Maybe nine.
我们要去度假
We're going on vacation.
爸爸告诉我，他会教我如何从码头上跳下来
My dad told me he'd teach me how to jump from the pier.
我在码头上
I'm on the pier.
我爸爸在水中他在打手势我，告诉我跳
My dad's in the water. He's gesturing me, telling me to jump.
“来吧，跳吧” 但是我不敢跳，我做不到
"Come on, jump." But I can't jump. I couldn't do it.
我觉得我父亲无法保护我
I felt my father wouldn't be able to protect me.
你明白我的意思吗？就好像……
Do you get what I'm saying? It felt as though...
好像他会伤害我，尽管是无意的
As though he could hurt me, albeit unintentionally.
好像我要淹死了，他也无法解救我
As though if I were to drown, he wouldn't be able to rescue me.
如果我发生什么事，他不会……
If something were to happen to me, he wouldn't...
我不能相信我的父亲！
I couldn't trust my father!
那天我不能相信我的父亲！
I couldn't trust my father on that day!
但是那只猫里面的东西
But whatever it was that was inside that cat...
我相信他 德瓦！
I trusted that thing, Deva!
妈妈，他有可能是你认识的人吗？
Could he be someone you know, mom?
-也许他认识你？-说什么傻话
- Or might he know you? - Don't be silly.
-我希望你认识他 -你祖父在哪里？
- I wish you did. - Where's your grandfather?
-嗯？-我问你你祖父在哪里
- Huh? - I asked you where your grandfather is.
他可能和他的女朋友在一起 我不知道
He might be with his girlfriend. I don't know.
天啊 德瓦……
Oh, Deva...
你好！
Hello!
-有人吗？-我马上来
- Is there anybody there? - I'll be right there.
你好，请问什么事？
Hello. How can I help you?
我正寻找……
I was looking for...
我不知道，小小的室内植物
I don't know, a small houseplant.
阿加？
Agah?
-阿加·贝尤鲁？-嗯？
- Agah Beyoglu? - Yes?
原谅我，我不确定我是否记得你
Forgive me, I'm not sure I remember you.
我是塞米尔的朋友 我叫泰丰 来自坎布拉！
It's Tayfun, Cemil's friend! From Kambura!
泰……
Tay...
泰丰！是你吗？
Tayfun! Is that you? No way!
-真是巧合！-你一点都没变
- What a coincidence! - You haven't changed one bit.
-你仍然像以前一样英俊 -别说了，我现在是个老人
- You're still as handsome as ever. - Stop it. I'm an old man now.
你最近好吗？你在这里做什么？
How are you doing? What are you doing here?
还行 这块地是我的，我在这里种各种各样的植物
Not much. I own this whole area. I cultivate all kinds of plants.
真好……
How nice. How...
我路过这里，需要一些室内植物
I was passing by and I needed some plants for the house.
当我看到这个地方时，我决定来看看
When I saw this place, I decided to stop by.
-太巧了 -别担心，我来帮你
- What a coincidence. - Don't worry, I've got you.
你以前很照顾我们
You used to take such good care of us.
你还记得你为我和塞米尔买的那些饭吗？
Do you remember all those meals you bought for Cemil and I?
那时我们是贫民窟的学生
We were dirt-poor students back then.
快坐吧 像在自己家一样
Come on. Take a seat. Make yourself at home.
你一定很忙 我不想耽误你时间
You must be busy. I wouldn't want to impose.
别说笑了 我已经把他们送回家了
Don't be ridiculous. I've sent the guys home.
快到关门的时间了 来吧 我们好好聊聊
It's almost closing time. Come on. Let's catch up.
-来-好吧
- Come on. - OK, then.
真是巧合 世界真小啊
What a coincidence. It's a small world, I'm telling you.
我们看到那辆车了 它直接开来这里
We have the vehicle in our sights. It's headed right to here.
好，先完成文书工作
Alright. Finish the paperwork first.
不要让他们起疑心 他可能有武器
Don't let them suspect anything. He might be armed.
当然
Of course.
跟随车辆，但要保持距离
Follow the vehicle, but keep your distance.
-谢谢你这么好 -当然
- Thank you. You're so kind. - Of course.
那你和塞米尔经常见面吗？
So? Do you and Cemil still see each other?
塞米尔太忙了 他是个重要人物
Cemil's too busy. He's become an important man.
他偶尔过来看看
He stops by now and again.
-你介意我喝点红酒吗？-当然不
- Would you mind if I had some raki? - Of course.
-每天的这个时候喝点酒最好了 -当然
- It goes down well at this time of day. - Of course.
-帮我清理头脑 -尽情享受
- Helps me clear my head. - Enjoy yourself.
-你喜欢喝咖啡吧？-是的 谢谢你
- You prefer coffee, right? - Yes. Thank you.
你要喝一杯吗？
You could join me, though. Would you like a glass?
不，我不喝
No. I shouldn't.
前几天，我去拜访一位朋友……
The other day, I was visiting a friend...
他摆好桌子，拿出一瓶红酒
He set a beautiful table and brought out a bottle of raki.
我们玩得很开心，但是过了一会儿，我开始感到非常难过
We were having so much fun, but after a while, I started feeling really bad.
-为什么？肚子不舒服吗？-不是的 我的记忆力减退
- Why? Was it your stomach? - No. Memory loss.
我忘了去那儿做什么
I forgot what I came there to do.
我体格不行了，你喝吧，不用管我
I don't have the constitution anymore. You enjoy yourself, I'm fine.
谢谢
Thank you.
靠边停
Pull over.
晚上好，请给我证件
Good evening. Papers, please.
晚上好，长官
Good evening, officer.
给你
Here.
我所有的证件都在那里
All my papers are there.
应该都是井然有序
Everything should be in order.
-我有地方要去 -等等，我还没检查
- I have somewhere to be. - Hold up. I haven't checked yet.
下车！下车！下车！
Get out! Out! Out!
下车！下车！
Get out! Get out of the car!
下车！下车！下车！
Get out! Out! Out, I said!
下车！
Get out!
举起手来！
Put your hands up!
把手都举起来，举起来！
Let me see your hands. Get up! Get up!
听着
Listen up.
他们抓住了哈姆萨
They have Hamza.
-那我应该说什么？-你应该说什么？
- So? What am I supposed to say? - What are you supposed to say?
哈姆萨会告诉他们他所知道的一切
Hamza will tell them everything he knows.
他们逼我们就手
They've forced our hand.
你还将告诉他们所有你知道的事情，乌拉尔
You're going to tell them everything you know, as well, Vural.
时刻记住乌福克
Keeping Ufuk in mind, of course.
明白了吗？
Is that clear?
当然
Of course.
-还剩几个？-这是最后一个
- How many left? - This is the last one.
-名字？-乌拉尔·亚斯莱
- Name? - Vural Yasl?.
继续
Go on.
坐吧 乌拉尔
Take a seat, Vural.
乌拉尔·亚斯莱……
Vural Yasl?... Yes.
告诉我坎布拉发生了什么
Go on. Tell me what happened in Kambura.
你是如何越狱的？谁帮助了你？
How did you escape from prison? Who helped you?
鹳
Storks.
鹳带我飞走了
Storks flew me away.
然后又飞了回来
Then flew me back.
谁能帮助像我这样的穷人？
Who would help a poor man such as I?
我当然是自己逃出来的
I escaped on my own, of course.
让自己进医院，从那里逃了出来
Got myself hospitalized, and escaped from there.
你的兄弟塔亚尔和他的家人在坎布拉死于火灾
Your brother Tayyar and his family died in a fire in Kambura.
你对此有什么了解？
What do you know about that?
我对此不太了解
I don't know much about it.
我哥哥喜欢喝酒
My brother liked to drink.
他是个酒鬼 他像海绵吸水一样喝酒
He was a drunk. He drank like a sponge.
但真的没办法 需要人来耕地
But you can't really help it. You need workers to till the fields.
他每年都来坎布拉 做各种各样的工作
He came to Kambura every year. Found a job to do one way or another.
他和他的家人一起工作
They worked, him and his whole family.
他们的房子着火了
A fire broke out at their house.
他的家人在那场大火中丧生，包括他所有的孩子
His family died in that fire, including all his children.
那件事使我抓狂了 我去了坎布拉
That drove me up the walls. I headed to Kambura.
我问他们发生了什么事
I asked them what happened.
他们告诉我起了火，是烟头引发的火灾
They told me there was a fire, started from a cigarette butt.
我也问了消防员和警察 他们说法都一样
I asked the fire brigade and the police. They all told me the same story.
当时有一个叫做哈里斯的人 他曾经在消防队，但他现在已经死了
There was this guy, Halis. He used to run the fire brigade. He's dead now.
他告诉我们，那是一支烟蒂引发的火灾
He told us it was a cigarette butt that started the fire.
那就是我们知道的一切了
That's what we all knew.
在我看来有些不对……
It didn't sit right with me...
那是一间很小的房子 我不知道为什么他们无法逃脱
It was a tiny house. I didn't get why they couldn't escape.
然后有两个年轻人来跟我说话 他们显然是孪生兄弟
Then two young men came to talk to me. They were brothers. Twins, apparently.
-一个叫塞菲还是什么 -另一个叫乌穆特？
- One was named Seyfi or something. - And the other's name, Umut?
可能是的，我记不清了
That might've been it. It's been a while.
-他们是乌福克的兄弟 -乌福克？
- They're Ufuk's brothers. - Ufuk?
他们实际上是三胞胎 你继续说
They're actually triplets. Go on with your story.
他们告诉我放下这件事 回家去
They told me to drop the subject and go home.
我问他们为什么 他们告诉我 我的兄弟塔亚尔，
I asked them why. They told me my brother, Tayyar,
在坎布拉强奸了一个年轻的女孩 而且不止一次
had raped a young girl from Kambura. And not once, at that. Again and again.
他们说他该死了
His time must've come, they said.
如果你还在这里闲逛 他们可能会决定
If you keep hanging around, they might decide
为那女孩向你复仇
to take her revenge on you, they said.
他们不是在谈论别人
They weren't talking about someone else.
他们是在威胁我
They were threatening me.
“由于你是塔亚尔的兄弟，你可能会死得很早”
"Since you're Tayyar's brother, you might die before your time."
他们原话说的是“他们会塞满你的洞”
"They'll plug you full of holes." That's exactly what they said.
内芙拉来到坎布拉 我们曾在门口说话
Nevra came to Kambura. We spoke in front of the house, in fact.
过了这么多年 我们在那里碰到了
That's where we ran into each other after all those years.
就在一周之前
It can't have been more than a week.
乌夫克知道了
Ufuk found out about it.
来找我，告诉我一个来自伊斯坦布尔的警察在那里要带他走
Came to me, told me a cop from Istanbul was there to take him away.
我问他他做了什么
I asked him what he'd done.
问他为什么
Asked him why...
他说：“我把那所房子烧毁了 我杀了那些人 ”
"I burned that house down," he said. "I killed those people."
但是他多年来一直在讲同样的故事
But he'd been singing the same refrain for years,
所以我没有当回事
so I didn't take him very seriously.
他曾经跟我提起过一个女孩
He told me about a girl then.
很显然是乌福克喜欢的人
There was apparently someone Ufuk had been pining after.
那个叫塔亚尔的混蛋强奸了她
That bastard named Tayyar raped her.
乌福克决定在大火中杀死他
Ufuk decided to kill him in a fire.
那天晚上
That was the night.
他去了房子，用铁链锁住了门窗
He went to the house and put chains around the exits.
然后他放了火
Then he started the fire.
我当然被惊呆了
I was stunned, of course.
这个女孩是谁？
Who is this girl?
塔亚尔强奸了谁？
Whom did Tayyar rape?
为什么我们都不知道这件事？
Why didn't we ever find out about it?
他也从没提到过
He didn't answer any of it. Just up and left.
我以为他又在幻想 他从来没有去过那里
I thought he was hallucinating again. He'd never been all there, you know.
但是事实证明 他确实把那所房子烧毁了
But it all turned out to be true. He really did burn that house down.
他为什么还要吊死自己？
Why else would he hang himself?
塔亚尔的妻子、孩子一直在都在房子里
Tayyar's family had been inside. His children, his wife.
全部死了
All dead.
谁可以忍受这些事？
Who could live with that knowledge?
我们看到了火焰，跑了过去
We saw the flames and ran over.
我们聚集在房子周围
We gathered around the house...
但是我们无能为力
But there was nothing we could do.
还记得那个消防员告诉我们那是烟头吗？
Remember that fireman who told us it was a cigarette butt?
已故的哈利斯？
The late Halis?
他一直在保护乌福克
He had been protecting Ufuk.
他一定知道真正发生了什么
He must've known what really happened.
他的兄弟们一定也知道
His brothers must've known also.
塞菲和乌穆特 愿上帝宽恕他们的罪过
Seyfi and Umut were their names. May God forgive their sins.
你认为你的兄弟真的有做吗？
Do you think your brother might've really done it?
-他真的强奸了那个女孩吗？-我不知道
- Could he really have raped that girl? - I don't know.
清醒的时候，他绝对不会做那样的事情，我敢肯定
He would never do something like that when sober. That, I'm certain of.
但是喝了酒我就不好说了
But drink? Drink turns people inside out.
你永远也不知道别人的真面目 即使是你的兄弟
You never know who people really are. Not even your own brother.
这就是为什么我离开了坎布拉
That's why I left Kambura.
他们有没有告诉你那个女孩是谁？
Did they tell you who the girl was?
-不，他们没有-你确定吗？
- No, they didn't. - Are you sure?
我不知道！
I don't know!
不，我不知道她是谁
No. I don't know who she was.
她一定很害怕
She must've been really scared.
她没有让别人知道
She didn't make herself known.
这么说吧 如果我们知道他的所作所为
Let me tell you something. If we'd known about what he did,
我们才是要烧房子的人
we would've been the ones to burn that house down.
我们会他妈的干翻他们全家人
We would've fucked his whole family.
我的意思是……当我说他妈的时 那只是一种说法 你懂的
I mean, when I say fuck... As a figure of speech, you understand.
我们永远不会碰他的妻子和他的孩子
We would never touch his wife and his kids.
-做事要有正确的方式 -正确的方式……
- There's a proper way of doing things. - A proper way...
要好好收拾他
You'd fuck him properly.
那时的村庄看起来不像今天
Back then, of course, villages didn't look like they do today.
他们是农村人
They were properly rural.
我在安纳托利亚的某个县，
I was in some county in Anatolia,
担任法院书记员
working as a court clerk.
我碰到了这个谋杀案
I come across this murder file.
我看着它，看看犯罪嫌疑人的陈述
I open it up and look at the suspect's statement.
他是18岁左右的年轻人
He's a young man. 18 or so.
父亲把他带到旁边
His father takes him aside,
告诉他家族的世仇
tells him about the blood feud his family's in.
事后他们调查了这件事 仇恨已经存在了六七十年
They looked into it after the fact. It had been going for 60-70 years.
两个家族 互相残杀
Two families, killing each other one by one.
总之 男孩的父亲告诉他 “轮到我们杀人了”
Anyway, the father says to his son, "It's our turn to take a life."
“你去做 你还年轻 不用做很久的牢”
"You're going to do it. You're young, you won't do much time."
男孩的父亲拿给他一把枪 是家族的传家宝
The boy's father brings out the gun. It's a family heirloom.
他们用同一把枪杀掉敌人，用了七十年
They've been using that same gun to kill their enemies for 70 years.
那时 父亲教他怎么用枪
Right there, the father teaches him how to use it.
“要这样装子弹，这样开枪”
"Here's how you load the chamber. Here's how you cock the gun."
父亲问他“你学会了吗？”男孩说“学会了”
"You got it?" his father asks the boy. "I got it," the boy says.
他手里拿着枪，向父亲射击
He takes the gun in his hand, and shoots his father. Just like that.
毫不犹豫
Doesn't even hesitate.
宪兵问他：“你为什么这样做？”
The gendarme asks him, "Why did you do it?"
“为什么呢？”男孩说：“我想结束仇恨”
"Why else?" says the boy. "I wanted to end the feud."
他们再次在法庭上问男孩
They ask the boy again in court.
“我们明白了，你想结束世仇，但是你怎么能枪杀你的父亲？”
"We get it, you wanted the feud to end. But how could you shoot your father?"
男孩说：“好吧，我一直恨我父亲”
"Well," the boy says, "I've always hated my father."
“我很久以前就想杀了他，但我没有枪”
"I would've killed him a long time ago, but I didn't have a gun."
-那是个好故事-是的
- That's some story. - It is.
世仇后来怎样了？结束了吗？
What about the blood feud? Did it end?
结束了，另一个家族感到困惑
It did. The other family was baffled.
仇恨结束了，但受苦的是男孩
The feud ended, but it was the boy that suffered for it.
他被判处无期徒刑 不是一直如此吗？
He was sentenced to life. Isn't that how it always goes?
年轻人永远是遭受苦难的人
The young are always the ones who end up suffering.
-电视上总能看到 -为什么这么说？
- It's all over the TV. - Why do you say that?
例如，为什么从来没有过一个老人用自杀式炸弹袭击？
Why hasn't there ever been an elderly suicide bomber, for example?
永远都是年轻人把自己炸飞
It's always the young who blow themselves up.
永远是年轻人 永远不会是老年人
It's always the young ones. Never the elderly.
年轻人死得如此之快，如此之轻易 这真是可惜
The young ones die so quick, so easily... It's a real pity.
他们的命毫无价值
Their lives have no value.
如果生命没有价值，那生命又会有什么意义呢？
How can there be a meaning to life if there is no value to it, right?
我们是怎么聊到这个话题的？
How have we gotten onto this subject?
我不知道 我一定是喝醉了
I don't know. I must be getting drunk.
总之 我不会打扰太久了 帮我找些植物我就走
Anyway. I've kept you too long. Give me some flowers and I'll go.
当然
Of course.
我要一些东西放在窗台上
I want something for the windowsill.
-什么样的？-这个 这里
- What would work? - Here. This one. Here.
-给你这个 -橡胶植物？
- I'll give you this one. - A rubber plant?
-是的，你需要每周浇两次水-好的
- Yeah. You need to water it twice a week. - Alright.
-它喜欢晒太阳，但是不要晒太多-当然
- It likes sunlight, but not too much. - Of course. Of course.
梅布鲁雷曾经很喜欢这些 我该给你多少钱？
Mebrure used to love these. What do I owe you?
-别提钱 -不行 我要付钱
- Don't even mention it. - No way. I want to pay for it.
-我不能拿你的钱 -当然可以
- I can't take your money. - Of course you can.
我知道我们是朋友，但这是生意
I know we're friends, but this is business.
-但是……-这是我们的第一笔交易
- But... - It's your first sale to me.
我希望能给你带来好运 非常感谢
I hope it brings you luck. Thank you so much. Thank you.
-你太客气了-别傻了
- You're too kind. - Don't be silly.
-非常感谢 给塞米尔带好 -当然 你要保重
- Thank you so much. Say hi to Cemil. - Of course. Take care.
-保重 -回见
- Take care. - Come back soon.
再见了 谢谢
Goodbye. Of course. Thank you. Thank you so much.
哦……
Oh...
袋子
The bag...
当然……
Of course...
天啊
Oh...
那是一次爆炸
That was some explosion.
我一定是把炸弹炸了
I must've went overboard with the bomb.
我差点要回去拿包 我真的开始忘记了
I almost went back for the bag. I'm starting to really lose it.
救救我 内芙拉
SAVE ME NEVRA